<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-28T23:28:14-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ryan N-D</title><author><name>Ryan Nance-Donaldson</name><email>ryan@ryannd.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">DeckRND</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/welcome/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DeckRND" /><published>2025-10-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/welcome/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="welcome">Welcome!</h1>

<p>Thanks for taking a look at the site, I’ve been wanting to start coding in public for a long time now.
Things are a bit sparse at the moment, but I have a couple big projects planned, as well as a goal to take on a few small projects on the side, and I’ll be keeping track of all that here 😊</p>

<h2 id="a-bit-about-me">A bit about me</h2>

<p>I’ve been a professional software engineer since 2021, and worn a few different hats in that time. I’ve worked in T3 support doing about everything you can imagine in a massive platform that managed an insane amount of information. I’ve lead a team through greenfield development on a project with loose guidelines and looser interpretations of done- and I’ve taken on traditional software development, working on projects that have tied all my knowledge and experience together in ways I never imagined.</p>

<p>Lately, I’ve found that I have a lot of room to grow. Through all these experiences, I’ve picked up a lot- but there are a thousand solutions to every problem, and I’ve only seen a few solutions so far. All this has made me realize that I’m at my best when I’m actively learning and building new things. I want to try to solve problems, then learn about how others have solved them to gather even better insights. I want to build things that someone might actually use, even if I’m the only “someone.” It feels more valuable to build something and fail than it does to dream about building something and never even start.</p>

<p>Besides coding, I collect hobbies like trading cards. I have loved Magic for years, been gaming for as long as I can remember, tinkering on computers since kindergarten, and more recently picked up fishing, hiking, camping, and, of course, knitting and crochet (it’s just so zen!). I’m sure I’ll find something new soon, and add it to the stack of things I would love to do if I only had more time 😉 For now, I’m trying to focus on getting some projects off the ground and actually deployed- and that should keep me pretty busy for the next 6 months at least!</p>]]></content><author><name>Ryan Nance-Donaldson</name><email>ryan@ryannd.com</email></author><category term="Welcome" /><category term="Projects" /><category term="Upcoming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DeckRND</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/deckrnd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DeckRND" /><published>2025-10-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/deckrnd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/deckrnd/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="deckrnd">DeckRND</h1>
<p>DeckRND is a one-stop shop for all your deck building shemes! Buy and sell cards at the Bazaar, track and optimize your deck on the Workbench, and keep tabs on your entire collection at a glance in the Vault.</p>

<p>This project is currently in the planning and early development phase. Be sure to follow for updates as they come out!</p>]]></content><author><name>Ryan Nance-Donaldson</name><email>ryan@ryannd.com</email></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Upcoming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[DeckRND DeckRND is a one-stop shop for all your deck building shemes! Buy and sell cards at the Bazaar, track and optimize your deck on the Workbench, and keep tabs on your entire collection at a glance in the Vault.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">harmonee</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/harmonee/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="harmonee" /><published>2025-10-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/harmonee</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/harmonee/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="family-harmonee">(Family) harmonee</h1>

<p>Keeping all the details together in a family is a tricky business- everybody has their own schedules, needs, preferences, and ideas, and things can easily get chaotic! Bring all these into harmonee, a private place to communicate, plan, and prepare for all the extra notes life throws our way. Your family can use harmonee to:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Make meals easier:
    <ul>
      <li>Easy filters to find the right recipe for each meal</li>
      <li>Plan meals a day, a week, or even a month in advance</li>
      <li>Create a shopping list in a click from your meal plan</li>
      <li>Share lists and recipes so they can add their favorites</li>
      <li>Keep track of the ingredients you have on hand with the in-app pantry</li>
      <li>Scan receipts to automatically add groceries, scan barcodes as you use items to remove them</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>See the due dates BEFORE they’re due:
    <ul>
      <li>Keep track of due dates, appointments, events, and schedules all in one place</li>
      <li>Easily add a list, task, or even a whole project to any calendar item</li>
      <li>Link your favorite calendar apps to share automatically</li>
      <li>Make a suggestion, and let your family weigh in on your event ideas!</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Work as a team:
    <ul>
      <li>Share lists, projects, ideas, and events with anybody you choose</li>
      <li>Set up roles and permissions to make sure those surprise party plans don’t get revealed too early</li>
      <li>Make requests that can be approved or denied by family guardians</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>We didn’t forget about the family who doesn’t live at home:
    <ul>
      <li>Connect households together with single use links right from the app</li>
      <li>Share whatever you want with connected families</li>
      <li>Create public spaces for all your clubs, groups, and hobbies</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Harmonee is currently in early, active development. Keep watch here as things develop!</p>]]></content><author><name>Ryan Nance-Donaldson</name><email>ryan@ryannd.com</email></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Upcoming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[(Family) harmonee]]></summary></entry></feed>